# MANU DWIVEDI

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Mobile: +91-8452866624
manu29.d@gmail.com
manu29d.github.io
https://www.linkedin.com/in/manu
29d/

#### **SUMMARY**

I have 8 years of experience working with many growth stage and established startups. I'm experienced in developing and maintaining scalable, extensible and reliable products. I believe myself to be highly analytical, empathetic and a curious team player. I love to teach and learn something everyday.

## **SKILLS**

- Ruby on Rails
- Javascript
- NodeJS
- React
- Docker
- Git

# **EDUCATION**

B.Tech, NIT Trichy, 2009-13

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Conducted seminar, "How to git gud", Computer Society of India (Mumbai)
- Industry mentor, Smart India Hackathon, Hyderabad and Mumbai
- 2nd runner-up, IBM-SwissRe hackathon, Bangalore

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Lead Software Engineer**

PlanSource India | April 2021 - Present

- Manage 2 teams of HPELs (10 members)
- Responsible for performance monitoring, mentoring and training of teams under me
- · Facilitate cross-functional communication and development

## Senior Software Engineer

Junglee Games Private Limited | April 2020 - Jan 2021

- · Worked on re-architecture and optimization of microservices
- POC on edge router implementation in Nodejs using express compliant middleware
- Worked as an individual contributor directly with architects and principal engineers

#### Senior Software Engineer

Curve Tomorrow | March 2017 - April 2019

- 100% test coverage across all projects
- Early employee, built culture and team from the ground up
- Reduced CI build times by ~60%
- Co-ordinate releases while working remote with teams spread in 5 time zones (4 countries, 3 continents)

## Senior Software Engineer

Talentica Software | Oct 2014 - Jan 2016

- Individual contributor in a distributed remote team
- Worked on Ruby on Rails, Angular v1 and BackboneJS

# Software Engineer

Kreatio Software | June 2013 - Oct 2014

- Upgraded Rails application from Rails 2 to Rails 4
- Setup and deployed new application in the smart classroom domain
- · Conducted trainings on ruby, git and NginX